[Music]
foreign
Advanced Training
so this is our
lesson 10 in terms of try sentence task
Advanced Training R it's a lesson 25 in
terms of overall present testoster
training
so in this lesson I'm gonna teach you
about the action mode constraint
so how can we use action mode constraint
why do we need to use
this action mode constraint and
when to use this action more constraint
so I'm going to explain you in this
particular session
please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos
thank you
okay first
so what are what is the agent items okay
so by end of this lesson you'll be able
to use the action mode constrained by
using latest present testoster 16
version
and we are also going to identify a
different scenarios where to use the
action mode constraint
see you know I mean if you know how to
use constraint but you have to know
in which scenarios you have to use this
action mode constraint right so I'm
gonna give you some examples and then we
are going to automate one of the example
by using Tristan 16. okay so constraint
is a type of action mode that allows you
to identify one specific item
in the list of similar items
okay so the item you are looking for
needs to be uniquely identifiable right
so to make it uniquely identifiable
within the similar items we are gonna
use an action Mode called constraint
okay so now let's jump onto the system
and see how
when
and why we need to use the action mode
constraint by using pressure test Tasker
so this is my uh try sentence Tasker
latest version 16. okay so before we
start working on this tricent testoster
16 let us first understand the scenario
that you would like to automate by using
constraint Okay so
so this is my demo webshop that we are
generally using throughout the sessions
right so this is my demo webshop so I am
in shopping cart
so if You observe the shopping cart here
I have three different products
one music two
the elect I mean it's a basically
downloadable digital file okay
with the price 10 and another one music
two with the price three
and one book with price 10. now let's
assume
so by mistake I have added one
additional
um digital basically one additional
digital downloadable into the shopping
cart I want to remove the second Music 2
with dollar three
so how can I remove that r i want to
remove a music too with dollar ten for
example okay I want to remove music two
with dollar 10. if you see in the card
I have the albums with the same title
music to hear
correct so that means I cannot directly
specify go and remove music too
let's say if I want to specify price 10
for example I want to remove
a product with price 10 but there is
another product which has a priced
either I cannot use music to or I cannot
use 10 because Music 2 has two similar
names if I specify price 10 it has two
products with same price
so I want to remove this music too of
price 10. so this is where we can start
using constraint to identify a unique
product within the shopping cart a
specific product within the shopping
cart even though there are
duplicate constraints or duplicate items
in the cart
right so now
what we are going to do I'm going to
login to the by using credentials and
then I'm gonna add multiple products
right and I want to remove one of the
music product which has a duplicate
interest with different prices
I want to remove one of the music
product
and then once I remove this product I
want to let's say if I remove this
product right remove this now my price
subtotal is 13. I want to make sure that
the product whatever I selected got
removed
once that product is removed your
product subtotal will be 13 correct so
that means the product got removed
successfully
okay
and then continue with our checkout
process and then complete your order
right that's what we are gonna do okay
so how can we achieve it
so let's say now let's go back to
our transientist task
so here
let's
uh
click on exercises under the exercises
you will find constrained folder okay
this is the test case that we are going
to automate okay I already
automated
some part of the test case basically we
are logging in
and then we are ordering the products
what products I'm ordering one jeans
product
and then I'm also ordering some music
album products that is Music 2 and music
two with ten dollars music two with
three dollars right just now we saw in
the cart I'm just adding into the chord
and then now our turn is to remove the
wrong
item which is music two with ten dollar
right I have to remove that okay so here
let's focus on that particular folder
what folder
remove wrong
item from the card right here first I am
doing I am actually clicking on
shopping cart
and now I need to remove a music product
with dollar ten how can I do that okay
so
for that let me add
a module shopping cart module Ctrl t
okay
shopping cart module I'm adding a
shopping cart model
and here let's rename this as
rename this as remove
wrong music so remove music from
shopping cart
remove
music
from
shopping cart
okay
and now
let's
see how can we remove the music
even though there are two duplicate
music items right so how can we do that
okay so here first shopping cart
products let's select this table this is
a table right so
I want to
specify this as select
okay once I select that particular table
you'll see here this is your entire
table this is your HTML table this
entire cart okay this is your HTML table
so I'm selecting the table once I select
the table
now I want to go I want to look for the
product column column called Product
this is my product column right this is
one column now I want to select the
product column so now rename this row
okay let me just quickly
sorry so now select row also here okay
under row select the action mode as
select
and now here
now under cell
I need to select a product column
correct
so now let's select the product here row
and select product
and here the product I want to
select constraint
what constraint I'm gonna instruct
Tasker to look for a product with title
music too
okay let's specify that music
this is my product
okay that is one constraint and now
again
here under row again
now this time rename this as sorry
so now I again
for
product here we selected product now I
want to provide a constraint of price
also prices should be 10 your title of
the product should be music two and
price should be 10 then only you select
it
not three earlier I already removed one
other product music two with 10 also
right so now here rename this cell this
time with price
and select constraint again
this is my constraint
and I am going to specify the price as
trick
10.00 hashtri so basically I'm using
regular expression so basically the
price should contain 10.00
so now what I'm instructing go to this
table
look for a product with music too
but that's not sufficient because music
to product has two different prices
three and ten and I'm also telling
Tasker look for price 10.
with title music too
right and now and now you need to again
now this time I have to
select remove if I find this constraint
you have to select remove check the
checkbox remove right now your cell
value should be
remove
D and then once you select remove the
corresponding checkbox see under this
column remove you have a checkbox so now
the checkbox should be true
see and now this should be
true I mean this should be your input
here remove should be select not verify
select
remove column under remove column
check the checkbox removed
right
so done once I check the checkbox
what I need to do I find the title of
music too and I find the price 10
select it and click on update shopping
cart
so here I need to
update the shopping cart button I need
to click on this so that's why I'm
specifying as X and your action mode
should be input
right
and now once I remove the product now I
need to verify the subtotal
so that I can make sure that the product
is removed and my subtotal should be the
the sum of only two products instead of
three products so here for that let's
insert
one more shopping cart one more time
let's insert
shopping cart
module one more time and this time let's
rename this as verify price
rename this as
verify price
I rename this as verify price
now here
you need to go to Price table now okay
because this is your price table this
entire thing is price table this is one
column this is your second column right
so here
first you need to
go to this column okay rename this as
has to because the price is at the
second column the price
so that's why I made it as hash2
and now
select your cell as subtotal I am
verifying subtotal correct
subtotal
and your subtotal should be 28 dollars
once I remove that particular duplicate
product okay and select your data type
as numeric
and select your action mode as verify
I am verifying the subtotal after
removing one of the music product with
ten dollars my subtotal should be 20
okay sorry 28 so let me just remove this
okay update this card
okay let's close this okay
I think
that is it
okay so now let's save this
and now let us run
let us run this okay
so here let us run this test case this
entire test case okay
right click and run
so as soon as you run it should open
your webshop and then it should add
three different products and it should
remove one product
see
it's clicked on login it's entered
username now it's gonna add blue jeans
first of 25
quantity with 25 quantity so which is 25
dollars
now it's going to add one music with ten
dollars and it is going to add another
music with three dollars it is totally
see 38 dollars
right I added total 38 dollars of the
worth but I'm gonna remove ten dollars
of Music see here it's going to see the
constraint now see it removed ten
dollars of Music two and then it's it's
checked your subtotal is 28 and then it
is checking out so that means even
though the shopping cart has some
duplicate
items with the same
properties are with same attributes by
using constraint
we are able to identify
the
item unique
right I specified a constraint of
both the constraints one is the
constraint of
price
sorry the music title title of the
product and the constraint of your price
right
so you see everything is passed see here
it use the constraint and the
corresponding music has been deleted
okay so your entire test case is pass
correct
hope you all understand
what kind of scenarios in which
scenarios you need to use the
constraint action mode
so where if there are similar controls
are there if there are similar list of
objects most of the times this
constraint is being used in the web
tables most of the times okay so if
there are similar list
of objects then if you want to identify
one of the object specific object then
you can specify the constraint
so that it can identify the
corresponding object unique
okay so if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
thank you
[Music]